<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scholarships / Assistantships on The Grad School Chronicles</title>
    <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/scholarships-/-assistantships/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scholarships / Assistantships on The Grad School Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hung Truong</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/scholarships-/-assistantships/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan SI ULA Position GET!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/30/university-of-michigan-si-ula-position-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/30/university-of-michigan-si-ula-position-get/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got a call from Lisa Gray-Lion regarding the status of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/11/university-of-michigan-library-associate-phone-interview/&#34;&gt;University Library Associates application&lt;/a&gt;. I think I said “yes” before she even officially asked me to accept!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll still have to fill out some paperwork, but I think it’s safe to announce this. The associates position pretty much relieves all the worries I had about getting financial support to go to grad school. I was looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Michigan&#34;&gt;University of Michigan entry&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia last night, and I learned that it’s the most expensive public school in the country for out of state students!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I don’t have to worry about finances anymore, I can safely say that I’ll be going to the University of Michigan in the Fall. I guess I should send in that letter, just to make it super official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m seriously excited about this. Because I’m not a typical librarian student, my job description will be more experimental and fun. Hopefully I can come up with a lot of good ideas on how to enhance the library with emerging technologies and the paradigms behind them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I just ordered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nike.com/index.jhtml#l=nikestore,grid,_pdp,cid-1/gid-114990/pid-114990,_grid,f-10002+12002+4294967258&amp;amp;re=US&amp;amp;co=US&amp;amp;la=EN&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan Library Associate Phone Interview</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/11/university-of-michigan-library-associate-phone-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/11/university-of-michigan-library-associate-phone-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I applied to the University of Michigan, I also sent an application for the Library Associates program. This program allows MS students to work in one of the university’s libraries and get real life work experience while also paying for school. The associates receive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full tuition waiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half-time, two-year appointment at University Library (1035 hours per year) with a salary of $21,657.80 per year (adjusted annually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eligibility to attend Library-sponsored workshops and training events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eligibility to choose from several health plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enrollment in group life insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wages are exempt from Social Security tax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Librarian borrowing privileges at the University Library, including free access to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umich.edu/7fast/&#34;&gt;7-FAST Delivery Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sixty hours of sick time per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much you get tuition waived and a nice salary. While I didn’t apply in the Library &amp;amp; Information Services specialization of the Information School, I still think the associate position would be really interesting and rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I think that emerging technologies could really make libraries more efficient. Since I have an interest in the information technology side of things, I think I could really contribute to the way that the library works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got an email a few days ago to schedule a phone interview for the position. I guess they liked the essay that I wrote. While I think that being offered the associate position is a long shot (there’s only one position open), I’m pretty glad they liked me enough to even set up a phone interview. Hopefully they’ll see me as a good fit for the position with my background in social computing programming and problem solving. I’ll be interviewing with them tomorrow, though I probably won’t know about a potential offer for a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
