<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Choosing a School on The Grad School Chronicles</title>
    <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/choosing-a-school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Choosing a School on The Grad School Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hung Truong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 13:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/choosing-a-school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan School of Information Visiting Days Impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-visiting-days-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-visiting-days-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote about my visit to the University of Michigan School of Information Visiting Days on my personal blog yesterday and forgot to put a link to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read about my experience &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/blog/2007/03/27/michigan-si-visiting-days-impressions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cliff Notes edition: I thought the program was nice, the people were incredible, and I feel very good about the program with only a few reservations that I can live with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in University of Michigan’s SI Specialization Choices</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/14/changes-in-university-of-michigans-si-specialization-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/14/changes-in-university-of-michigans-si-specialization-choices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got an email from Judith Olson about some changes in the specialization choices at The University of Michigan’s School of Information MSI program. Originally I had applied under the HCI (Human Computer Interaction) specialization because it was the closest thing to what I really wanted to study, Social Computing. I’m happy to see that Social Computing has its own specialization in the MSI program now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really cool! When I was shopping around for grad schools, I found none that really specialized in Social Computing. Now that I’ve been accepted into Michigan, they added a Social Computing specialization. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting to see if I can get a job offer at Google, but this announcement adds a few weights on the scale of Michigan. I’m also waiting on the offer for that University Library Associates thing at Michigan. I have a feeling that deciding is going to be much tougher than waiting…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be sure to ask a ton of questions when I’m at the visiting days at Michigan on March 24-26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the email; it also lists a few other specializations that are kinda cool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at the School of Information are excited to announce the addition of several new specializations to our Master of Science in Information program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Computing&lt;br&gt;
Information Policy&lt;br&gt;
Community Informatics&lt;br&gt;
Information Analysis and Retrieval&lt;br&gt;
Preservation of Information&lt;br&gt;
Incentive-Centered Design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the information field matures as a professional discipline, areas of focus and career paths within the field are becoming more established. Our new specializations recognize some of these paths and are designed to help you more closely match your MSI experience to your career goals and the expanding job market for information professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These six new tracks join our current specializations in archives and records management, human-computer interaction, and library and information services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve grown our specialization in information economics, management and policy (IEMP) into several distinct areas. Information policy will be its own specialization, and information economics will be a primary focus of the incentive-centered design specialization. Information management is an area so central to the skill set of an information professional that we have incorporated it as a core component of the entire MSI program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students who enter the MSI program in the fall of 2007 wishing to specialize in IEMP may still do so, or they may focus on one or two of the newer specializations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though these six are newly identified as specializations at SI, they are all areas in which we have been building expertise and curriculum for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the new specializations — information analysis and retrieval (IAR) and incentive-centered design — have matured from earlier academic clusters within the School. IAR focuses on how information is stored, searched, and analyzed in computer systems (the current darling in this realm is of course Google). Incentive-centered design develops systems that align users’ motivations with the organizations overall goals. It draws deeply from economics, psychology, and sociology, with computer science as a unifying thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community informatics specialization recognizes the foresight of the School’s Community Information Corps, or CIC. Established in 2001, the CIC has led nationally in the development and professionalization of what’s now a widely recognized career track — the professional who deploys information and communication technologies in service of the public good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our specialization in social computing, the force driving Web 2.0, also develops from this focus on communities and information. It brings together our work and curriculum in the areas of social networking and user-contributed content systems. Social computing is a force so pervasive it led Time magazine to name “you” person of the year in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preservation of information specialization grows from our unique strengths in archives and records management and responds to the urgent need for expertise in preservation, digital curation, and Web archiving within all information-rich organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new specializations comes added flexibility. It’s now possible to complete your MSI with *two* specializations, and a number of courses can be counted for more than one specialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evolution of these new specializations at SI marks the evolution of the information field as a whole and validates the trail SI has blazed over more than a decade of innovation as the School of Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about these expanded offerings at &lt;a href=&#34;http://si.umich.edu/go&#34;&gt;http://si.umich.edu/go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information field is our future, and our future is here. Join us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even More Grad Schools That I Might Possibly Apply To</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/even-more-grad-schools-that-i-might-possibly-apply-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/even-more-grad-schools-that-i-might-possibly-apply-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reader demaws commented on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/my-application-list-for-computer-science-and-related-schools/&#34;&gt;Application List&lt;/a&gt; with a few other schools. I figured I should take a quick look at them to see if they’re application worthy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carnegie-mellon&#34;&gt;Carnegie Mellon &lt;a href=&#34;#carnegie-mellon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hcii.cmu.edu/&#34;&gt;Master’s in HCI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 31st, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Carnegie Mellon is one of the more highly ranked and prestigious schools out there. Their HCI program is different from many others because it only takes a year to finish. The program runs from Fall of a given year to the Summer of the next. The website states that the program does not financially support its students, but occasionally a teaching assistantship will come up for students with a CS background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like there would really be no time to do research while taking so many courses in one semester, on top of doing a teaching assistantship! There is a part time option, so I could probably apply with that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iowa-state-university&#34;&gt;Iowa State University &lt;a href=&#34;#iowa-state-university&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hci.iastate.edu/description.php&#34;&gt;Master’s in Human Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 1st, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Apparently, the HCI program at Iowa State is very highly ranked. I took a look at their website. It looks like they have some interesting courses. For example, “Interaction Methods for Emerging Technologies” and “Organizational and Social Implications of Human Computer Interaction.” Also noteworthy is that that “All students accepted into the HCI program will receive a half-time graduate assistantship.” I’m not really sure what that means. I guess that all students can go part time fully paid. I’ll have to email and ask though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it seems that they have a pre-application before the actual application. Luckily, the pre application is free, so I’ll probably be taking advantage of that fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-of-maryland&#34;&gt;University of Maryland &lt;a href=&#34;#university-of-maryland&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: Master’s in Computer Science, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.umd.edu/hcil/&#34;&gt;HCI Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Deadline: December 15th, 2006&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Maryland has a Human Computer Interaction research group, but no actual department. Therefore, I’d have to apply to CS and then do research within the HCI group. Their group certainly looks like a lively bunch of people. Unfortunately, the deadline is in… 5 days. So I don’t think I’ll be applying due to time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stanford&#34;&gt;Stanford &lt;a href=&#34;#stanford&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: MS in Computer Science, &lt;a href=&#34;http://hci.stanford.edu/&#34;&gt;HCI Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Deadline: December 12th, 2006&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Stanford has a pretty rockin’ HCI group too, it seems. Unfortunately, it’s Stanford, and I’m not a perfect robot. Also, the deadline is in two days, which is kind of cutting it close… I’d apply if I thought I had a chance, and if I could turn back time (which would probably look good in my resume).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got a Reply From Berkeley’s iSchool</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/got-a-reply-from-berkeleys-ischool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/got-a-reply-from-berkeleys-ischool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow up from the last post, I got a reply regarding a few questions I had about Berkeley’s iSchool. Mainly, I just reiterated my concerns about the perceived legitimacy of “Information Schools” opposed to pure Computer Science. I also asked about the availability of funding for Master’s students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reply was that the reputation of the program over at Berkeley is rising. Of course, I’ll take that info with a grain of salt, but the person who replied to me said that many companies like to recruit at the iSchool, and had some other facts to back up the claim. My question about funding was answered more indirectly. I was just told that there exist many research opportunities with companies. They also mentioned that Yahoo has a research lab at Berkeley, which is kinda cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m glad that someone at Berkeley spent the time to answer my questions. Now I’m just waiting on UC Irvine and Georgia Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacting Grad Schools, And Waiting For Replies…</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/07/contacting-grad-schools-and-waiting-for-replies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/07/contacting-grad-schools-and-waiting-for-replies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last post, I mentioned that the University of Michigan had a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://mblog.lib.umich.edu/sitrenches1/&#34;&gt;admissions blog&lt;/a&gt; that included a contact email in case any prospective students had questions. I actually had a few questions, so I decided to send an email. I also figured that I should send emails to all of the institutions that I was thinking of applying to. I sent similar emails (though they each had specific questions about each program) to Georgia Tech, Virginia Tech, UC Irvine, and Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a very long and thoughtful response from Laura Elgas at Michigan. Her email really went above and beyond what I was expecting to receive. She answered all of my questions and even offered to set up a telephone appointment so I could speak with her directly! Suffice it to say, I have a very positive impression of the program at Michigan now. It really means a lot to me that a real human would reply and help me out with this difficult process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got a personal reply from Virginia Tech. They simply stated that I seemed to be a good match with their program based on the info I told them (I also sent them the URL for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notecentric.com/&#34;&gt;Notecentric&lt;/a&gt;). Most of my questions were answered, though they skipped a few. They politely asked that I keep in touch once I’ve actually submitted my application. This is about on par with what I would expect to receive. I understand that most schools don’t have much time to respond personally to emails, so the reply I got very much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both UC Irvine and Berkeley sent me automatic replies. The UC Irvine one had a lot of general grad school information. It said that I should send the message again if my questions weren’t answered. I did. The Berkeley email just stated that I should be receiving a reply shortly. This was five days ago. Hopefully I’ll get something from both of them soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Georgia Tech sent me nothing. Incidentally, I had sent a message to them a month or so ago that didn’t get a reply either. I don’t know who’s running the recruiting over at Georgia Tech, but they haven’t impressed me. I really don’t expect to get a reply from them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in summary, Michigan is really awesome at recruiting, VT is good. UC Irvine and Berkeley still haven’t sent me anything, but it’s only been 5 days. Still a long turnaround time, I think. Georgia Tech doesn’t seem to care about its prospective students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some schools have made me feel very excited to apply, others have given me the cold shoulder. While the academic strength of a program is really important, I think that the people skills of a department really reflect a lot as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Additional Schools That I Might Apply To</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/26/some-additional-schools-that-i-might-apply-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/26/some-additional-schools-that-i-might-apply-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found a few more schools that have good looking programs that I’d be interested in applying to. With these two, my school count would go up to 7. I’m not too sure that’s playing it too safe, or not safe enough. Here are the additional schools and my reasoning for wanting to apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cornell&#34;&gt;Cornell &lt;a href=&#34;#cornell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infosci.cornell.edu/grad/&#34;&gt;PhD in Information Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 1, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Cornell has a program similar to a few of the schools that I’m already planning on applying to. Right now, they only have a PhD program in Information Science, so I’d have to go that route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not really too opposed to applying as a PhD student; I’m just not completely sure about studying for another 4-5 years as opposed to 2 years. The program at Cornell seems fairly multidisciplinary, with courses in communication, cognition, and social aspects of information. It seems like a nice program, if I can get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-of-michigan&#34;&gt;University of Michigan &lt;a href=&#34;#university-of-michigan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.umich.edu/msi/default.htm&#34;&gt;Master of Science in Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: February 5th, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: The University of Michigan offers a Masters degree in Information. The program offers courses like “Design of Complex Web Sites” and “Computer-Supported Cooperative Work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing I found was that the website had &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.umich.edu/applying/subscribe.htm&#34;&gt;links to school blogs&lt;/a&gt;. There were a few from students, as well as an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mblog.lib.umich.edu/sitrenches1/&#34;&gt;Admissions Blog&lt;/a&gt;. The admissions blog seems to have been set up specifically to help prospective students through the process. Very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Application List For Computer Science and Related Schools</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/my-application-list-for-computer-science-and-related-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/my-application-list-for-computer-science-and-related-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After taking quite a bit of time considering schools and departments, I’ve come up with a list of schools I’ll be applying to. I suppose they’re still subject to change, but here’s what I’ve got (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;georgia-tech&#34;&gt;Georgia Tech &lt;a href=&#34;#georgia-tech&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/content/view/731/464/&#34;&gt;MS in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: February 1, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Georgia Tech seems to be one of the more, if not the most progressive schools in the nation when it comes to computer science. Their MS program in HCI has a bunch of interesting courses like Design of Online Communities and Collaborative Computing. In addition to the MS in HCI, the MS in CS also allows students to specialize in a field. The fields include intelligent systems, networking and communications, and HCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virginia-tech&#34;&gt;Virginia Tech &lt;a href=&#34;#virginia-tech&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hosting.cs.vt.edu/gpc/MSreqts.html&#34;&gt;MS in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 15, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Virginia Tech is one of the few schools that i found that has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hci.vt.edu/&#34;&gt;HCI group&lt;/a&gt;. Virginia Tech is fairly well ranked in terms of Engineering schools. Another plus is that they seem to offer good funding to their MS thesis students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uc-irvine&#34;&gt;UC Irvine &lt;a href=&#34;#uc-irvine&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/grad/degrees/index.php?track=inf-ict&#34;&gt;MS in Interactive and Collaborative Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 15, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: UC Irvine is one of the schools I wrote about earlier with a specialized degree program. In this case, the field is referred to as “Informatics.” They have their own &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/%7Ecorps/&#34;&gt;ICT group&lt;/a&gt; which is a huge plus in terms of research capability. “Interactive and Collaborative Technology” is exactly what I’d like to do research in, and I’m hopeful that I’ll be accepted into the program. Apparently, their MS students have a chance to get financial assistance through teaching assistantships and whatnot, so I’ll apply for the MS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lehigh-university&#34;&gt;Lehigh University &lt;a href=&#34;#lehigh-university&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www3.lehigh.edu/engineering/cse/academics/grad/masterscicompsci.asp&#34;&gt;MS in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 15, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: I had never heard of Lehigh University until I saw the name on multiple top engineering school lists. After doing some research, it seems like Lehigh is a good fit for me, since it includes a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wume.cse.lehigh.edu/&#34;&gt;Web Understanding, Modeling, and Evaluation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. It appears that Lehigh is preparing to branch its Computer Engineering program into an Intelligent Information Systems Engineering and Software Systems Engineering as well, so it might be a good time for me to apply to their program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uc-berkeley&#34;&gt;UC Berkeley &lt;a href=&#34;#uc-berkeley&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ischool.berkeley.edu/programs/masters&#34;&gt;MS in Information Sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 5, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: The iSchool at Berkeley is relatively new: the school was created in 1994. The school is also very small. Only 40 of 200 master’s students are accepted each year. I have a feeling that the projects that I’ve done might make me interesting to the school, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll try using the iSchool as my “long shot” school and just apply to see if I can make it. The courses all seem very cool, with names like “XML Foundations” and “The Quality of Information.” I would really love to get into this school, as it seems like they’re on the forefront of this field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Degree in Computer Science vs. Information Technology vs. Informatics?</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/06/graduate-degree-in-computer-science-vs.-information-technology-vs.-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/06/graduate-degree-in-computer-science-vs.-information-technology-vs.-informatics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So getting a bachelor’s degree in Computer Science was a pretty easy decision for me to make. There’s not a “Computer Engineering” degree at my school, and “Electrical Engineering” is too circuity for my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to do research in stuff like social computing and computational linguistics. While looking for departments with research in these fields, it’s become evident this kind of research doesn’t typically fall in the Computer Science field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computational linguistics stuff falls under the linguistics departments for a lot of schools. While I like the idea of researching more linguistics, I don’t know if I want to get a graduate level degree in it. It would make more sense to me to get a MD or PhD in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social computing field is actually fairly new. It seems like more and more schools are starting “Information Technology” departments that are separate from their Computer Science ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such school is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rit.edu/&#34;&gt;Rochester Institute of Technology&lt;/a&gt;. RIT even has a section of its website dedicated to explaining the differences between &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.it.rit.edu/it/undergrad/whichpathBS.maml&#34;&gt;Information Technology, Computer Science, Software Engineering, Computer Engineering and Information Systems&lt;/a&gt; by likening it to the development of a video game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computer engineer would design the actual game platform, the hardware and low-level software. The software engineer would design the software architecture in which specific games would be developed and facilitate on-time development of reliable components. The computer scientist would develop efficient underlying algorithms for the game engines. The IT professional would focus on specific games from the player’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, I’d see myself as either a software engineer, computer scientist, or IT person. When it’s described like this, none of the degrees seem “bad.” I think, however, that there’s a sort of stigma when talking about “IT” people. Mainly the idea that they’re the “tech support guy” who fixes dumb peoples’ computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found yet another “new” degree at UC Irvine called the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/grad/degrees/index.php?track=inf-ict&#34;&gt;“Concentration in Informatics Track in Interactive and Collaborative Technology.”&lt;/a&gt; This one really seems to fit the bill in terms of the type of research and learning that I want to do. UC Irvine even has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/%7Ecorps/&#34;&gt;ICT&lt;/a&gt; (Interactive and Collaborative Technologies) group with a bunch of people I’d probably like working with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, I think the only reservation I’d have is getting into a relatively “new” degree program, and the perceived “illegitimacy” when compared to a PhD in the almighty “Computer Science!” Then again, it might be time for the monolithic Computer Science degree to be broken into smaller, more specialized fields of study…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last “alternative” graduate program that I’ll mention is at Georgia Tech. They offer an MS in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/content/view/731/464/&#34;&gt;“Human-Computer Interaction”&lt;/a&gt; and a PhD in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/content/view/190/136/&#34;&gt;“Human-Centered Computing.”&lt;/a&gt; Georgia Tech really seems to be one of the more progressive schools when it comes to computing degrees, and I’d be really happy to go there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I read about these alternative graduate programs, the more I think that a standard graduate degree in Computer Science is becoming less relevant in a quickly changing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do you think? Is the traditional Computer Science track the way to go? Are these new fangled degrees nothing but semantic sugar? Please let me know in the comments, as I’m not quite decided on this myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to The Grad School Chronicles!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/welcome-to-the-grad-school-chronicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 15:12:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/welcome-to-the-grad-school-chronicles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is yet another blog for me, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hung-truong.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Hung Truong&lt;/a&gt;, to keep up to date. I’ve been searching for CS Graduate Schools and thought it would be a good idea to impart the information I’ve gained onto the web. Most graduate school info online tends to be dry and written from the perspective of someone who’s been through it all already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog will be written by someone who’s still figuring out the process, so hopefully it’ll also be helpful to others who are going through the same thing. I’m still in the very early stages of the grad school process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, this blog will chronicle the steps I take from figuring out how to apply, collecting the letters of acceptance, choosing which school to go to, and then my experiences during grad school itself. Hopefully I’ll get past the second step, at least!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned quite a big just from talking to professors and advisers. Stuff that isn’t really available online, either. In addition to writing about what I’m doing to further the process, I’ll also try to post tips and information that I think is not so common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting, and I hope you get some use out of The Grad School Chronicles*!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*At least until I come up with a better name!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
