<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Grad School Chronicles</title>
    <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Grad School Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hung Truong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 13:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Graduated!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2009/07/18/i-graduated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2009/07/18/i-graduated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, guess what? This version of WordPress is really old, I haven’t updated this blog in forever, and I graduated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep this thing around because I think many people have used it as a resource. Also, who knows if I might someday try for a PhD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, have a great summer, stay cool, K.I.T. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Worry, I’m Still in Grad School…</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2008/01/08/dont-worry-im-still-in-grad-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2008/01/08/dont-worry-im-still-in-grad-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just hardly post on this blog anymore. But I do post on my personal blog. It just sorta makes more sense that way, since it usually has a higher readership on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I posted my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/blog/2008/01/06/internship-searching-season-2008/&#34;&gt;thoughts on the current internship hunt that I’m facing&lt;/a&gt;. I thought it might be useful for people who have already gotten into grad school, and who are looking for a good internship for the Summer. I don’t have a complete list of internships for social computing-minded people, but I have a start…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iowa State: Super Late Rejection!!!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/06/01/iowa-state-super-late-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/06/01/iowa-state-super-late-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got a rejection email from Iowa State. They certainly took their time to inform me of my rejection!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of Jim Oliver, HCI graduate program chair, thank you very much for your application to our graduate program. We are very pleased to be able to consider students such as you. However, we only accept students for whom we can provide research assistantships. Unfortunately, we receive applications from many more highly qualified students than we are able to support. We, therefore, cannot offer you admission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trust that you will be admitted elsewhere and wish you the best of luck in your graduate studies. Thank you again for considering Iowa State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already accepted over at Michigan, so this is kind of pointless to post. Except that it’s way funny seeing this email in June. Ah well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Irvine Bren School of ICS: Rejection!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/uc-irvine-bren-school-of-ics-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/uc-irvine-bren-school-of-ics-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I applied to the UC Irvine Bren School of ICS under the informatics track. Sadly, today I was denied admission via email. So now I’m 2 for 6 in applying to grad schools with 3 of the 4 rejections being concrete, and one in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UC Irvine did seem like a pretty cool place to apply for grad school, so I’m a little bummed that I didn’t meet their requirements. Looking at it geographically, it looks like I did better the farther NorthEast I went. Maybe I should’ve applied at MIT!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virginia Tech Computer Science Program: Acceptance!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/virginia-tech-computer-science-program-acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/virginia-tech-computer-science-program-acceptance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a letter in the mail today from Virginia Tech. Surprisingly, it was an acceptance letter! I got into their CS program! Pretty cool. The letter came fairly late, though, and without any mention of scholarships, so I’m assuming I’m one of their second or third tier choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve already accepted to go to Michigan (with a nice funding package), but it’s nice to see that I made it into another program at least. I think the program at Virginia Tech is actually pretty competitive, so it makes me feel better about being rejected from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/05/university-of-california-berkeley-ischool-rejection/&#34;&gt;Berkeley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/georgia-tech-hci-program-rejection/&#34;&gt;Georgia Tech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My record is now 2 of 6, with 2 being rejections and 2 not yet known. Like I said though, it doesn’t really matter since I got into my top school, but pride-wise, this makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan SI ULA Position GET!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/30/university-of-michigan-si-ula-position-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/30/university-of-michigan-si-ula-position-get/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got a call from Lisa Gray-Lion regarding the status of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/11/university-of-michigan-library-associate-phone-interview/&#34;&gt;University Library Associates application&lt;/a&gt;. I think I said “yes” before she even officially asked me to accept!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll still have to fill out some paperwork, but I think it’s safe to announce this. The associates position pretty much relieves all the worries I had about getting financial support to go to grad school. I was looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Michigan&#34;&gt;University of Michigan entry&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia last night, and I learned that it’s the most expensive public school in the country for out of state students!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I don’t have to worry about finances anymore, I can safely say that I’ll be going to the University of Michigan in the Fall. I guess I should send in that letter, just to make it super official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m seriously excited about this. Because I’m not a typical librarian student, my job description will be more experimental and fun. Hopefully I can come up with a lot of good ideas on how to enhance the library with emerging technologies and the paradigms behind them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I just ordered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nike.com/index.jhtml#l=nikestore,grid,_pdp,cid-1/gid-114990/pid-114990,_grid,f-10002+12002+4294967258&amp;amp;re=US&amp;amp;co=US&amp;amp;la=EN&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan School of Information Visiting Days Impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-visiting-days-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-visiting-days-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote about my visit to the University of Michigan School of Information Visiting Days on my personal blog yesterday and forgot to put a link to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read about my experience &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/blog/2007/03/27/michigan-si-visiting-days-impressions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cliff Notes edition: I thought the program was nice, the people were incredible, and I feel very good about the program with only a few reservations that I can live with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgia Tech, HCI Program: Rejection!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/georgia-tech-hci-program-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/georgia-tech-hci-program-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so this news is sorta late, but I figured I’d post this anyway. Remember how I wrote about how Georgia Tech wasn’t responding to my emails? I finally got a response! A rejection! Yeah, that’s right, Georgia Tech only takes the time to respond to a candidate when they’re rejecting them. How nice. Here’s the letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Hung:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry to inform you that your application to Georgia Tech’s MS program in Human-Computer Interaction has been declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many applicants we are not able to admit. The applicant pool was significantly larger than in recent years, and the overall quality of applicants even higher than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like advice on strengthening your application and trying again next year, I’ll be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have our best wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least they offered to give me advice on helping my application. I actually emailed them back immediately and got an “out of town” autoreply. So they wrote me this denial from out of town?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not too upset about this. Georgia Tech showed that they didn’t care about their MS students even before sending me this rejection. I spoke with some other students at the University of Michigan visiting days and there was pretty much a consensus that Georgia Tech treats their MS students with dollar signs in their eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in University of Michigan’s SI Specialization Choices</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/14/changes-in-university-of-michigans-si-specialization-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/14/changes-in-university-of-michigans-si-specialization-choices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got an email from Judith Olson about some changes in the specialization choices at The University of Michigan’s School of Information MSI program. Originally I had applied under the HCI (Human Computer Interaction) specialization because it was the closest thing to what I really wanted to study, Social Computing. I’m happy to see that Social Computing has its own specialization in the MSI program now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really cool! When I was shopping around for grad schools, I found none that really specialized in Social Computing. Now that I’ve been accepted into Michigan, they added a Social Computing specialization. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still waiting to see if I can get a job offer at Google, but this announcement adds a few weights on the scale of Michigan. I’m also waiting on the offer for that University Library Associates thing at Michigan. I have a feeling that deciding is going to be much tougher than waiting…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be sure to ask a ton of questions when I’m at the visiting days at Michigan on March 24-26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the email; it also lists a few other specializations that are kinda cool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at the School of Information are excited to announce the addition of several new specializations to our Master of Science in Information program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Computing&lt;br&gt;
Information Policy&lt;br&gt;
Community Informatics&lt;br&gt;
Information Analysis and Retrieval&lt;br&gt;
Preservation of Information&lt;br&gt;
Incentive-Centered Design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the information field matures as a professional discipline, areas of focus and career paths within the field are becoming more established. Our new specializations recognize some of these paths and are designed to help you more closely match your MSI experience to your career goals and the expanding job market for information professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These six new tracks join our current specializations in archives and records management, human-computer interaction, and library and information services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve grown our specialization in information economics, management and policy (IEMP) into several distinct areas. Information policy will be its own specialization, and information economics will be a primary focus of the incentive-centered design specialization. Information management is an area so central to the skill set of an information professional that we have incorporated it as a core component of the entire MSI program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students who enter the MSI program in the fall of 2007 wishing to specialize in IEMP may still do so, or they may focus on one or two of the newer specializations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though these six are newly identified as specializations at SI, they are all areas in which we have been building expertise and curriculum for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the new specializations — information analysis and retrieval (IAR) and incentive-centered design — have matured from earlier academic clusters within the School. IAR focuses on how information is stored, searched, and analyzed in computer systems (the current darling in this realm is of course Google). Incentive-centered design develops systems that align users’ motivations with the organizations overall goals. It draws deeply from economics, psychology, and sociology, with computer science as a unifying thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community informatics specialization recognizes the foresight of the School’s Community Information Corps, or CIC. Established in 2001, the CIC has led nationally in the development and professionalization of what’s now a widely recognized career track — the professional who deploys information and communication technologies in service of the public good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our specialization in social computing, the force driving Web 2.0, also develops from this focus on communities and information. It brings together our work and curriculum in the areas of social networking and user-contributed content systems. Social computing is a force so pervasive it led Time magazine to name “you” person of the year in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preservation of information specialization grows from our unique strengths in archives and records management and responds to the urgent need for expertise in preservation, digital curation, and Web archiving within all information-rich organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new specializations comes added flexibility. It’s now possible to complete your MSI with *two* specializations, and a number of courses can be counted for more than one specialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evolution of these new specializations at SI marks the evolution of the information field as a whole and validates the trail SI has blazed over more than a decade of innovation as the School of Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about these expanded offerings at &lt;a href=&#34;http://si.umich.edu/go&#34;&gt;http://si.umich.edu/go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information field is our future, and our future is here. Join us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan Library Associate Phone Interview</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/11/university-of-michigan-library-associate-phone-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/11/university-of-michigan-library-associate-phone-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I applied to the University of Michigan, I also sent an application for the Library Associates program. This program allows MS students to work in one of the university’s libraries and get real life work experience while also paying for school. The associates receive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full tuition waiver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half-time, two-year appointment at University Library (1035 hours per year) with a salary of $21,657.80 per year (adjusted annually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eligibility to attend Library-sponsored workshops and training events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eligibility to choose from several health plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enrollment in group life insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wages are exempt from Social Security tax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Librarian borrowing privileges at the University Library, including free access to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umich.edu/7fast/&#34;&gt;7-FAST Delivery Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sixty hours of sick time per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much you get tuition waived and a nice salary. While I didn’t apply in the Library &amp;amp; Information Services specialization of the Information School, I still think the associate position would be really interesting and rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I think that emerging technologies could really make libraries more efficient. Since I have an interest in the information technology side of things, I think I could really contribute to the way that the library works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got an email a few days ago to schedule a phone interview for the position. I guess they liked the essay that I wrote. While I think that being offered the associate position is a long shot (there’s only one position open), I’m pretty glad they liked me enough to even set up a phone interview. Hopefully they’ll see me as a good fit for the position with my background in social computing programming and problem solving. I’ll be interviewing with them tomorrow, though I probably won’t know about a potential offer for a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of California, Berkeley iSchool: Rejection!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/05/university-of-california-berkeley-ischool-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/05/university-of-california-berkeley-ischool-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got an email from the iSchool at Berkeley. It reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The admissions committee of the School of Information has reviewed all of the materials submitted with your application. I regret to inform you that you have not been accepted for admission to the Fall 2007 entering class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well! I’m pretty happy that I got accepted to Michigan already. Berkeley looked like a pretty good school, but it was my “probably too hard to get in” one, so I don’t feel too bad. I wonder if all of the schools will be sending these admission messages through email… Seems to be a new trend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan School of Information Scholarship Update!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/01/michigan-school-of-information-scholarship-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/01/michigan-school-of-information-scholarship-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got an email today from Michigan offering me a half tuition merit scholarship! This brings the cost of tuition down to the same amount that an in-state resident would pay. Scholarship students also get travel expenses refunded in order to visit the school on the SI: Visiting Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visiting days include an optional tour of the campus, housing, or libraries, and then a few activities with some of the student groups. It seems like fun, and I’d really like to be able to visit a school before committing to going there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully everything will work out and I’ll be able to visit on the scheduled day. I’m actually going to be out of town on the day before, so I’d have to fly directly to Michigan. I can probably make it work, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan School of Information Acceptance Email Received!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/02/22/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-acceptance-email-received/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/02/22/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-acceptance-email-received/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received a letter of acceptance from the University of Michigan School of Information. It was one of my top choices, so I’m happy to be accepted for admission. Actually, right now it’s a “conditional” admission, since they said they’re having issues with my official transcript, but I’m sure that won’t be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still haven’t heard anything about possible financial aid or scholarships yet. Hopefully I’ll be offered something. I think it would be very hard for me to go to school for more than $14,000 a semester without any assistance. Maybe I’ll receive that information at a later date. Edit: I got an email saying that the financial aid offers will be given in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m very happy about getting the email. I hope the other schools will send their Acceptance/Rejection (I hope not!) letters soon. One thing I found interesting was that Michigan sent me the acceptance letter by email. I think almost all schools will only send this information out by snail mail. Not that it’s bad or anything, I’d rather find out as soon as possible! It’s pretty cool that Michigan is hip enough with technology to use email though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official GRE Scores Breakdown!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/01/16/official-gre-scores-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/01/16/official-gre-scores-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got my official GRE scores back. They were the same as the “unofficial” ones that I got right after I took the test. For the verbal, I got a 590 which was in the 83 percentile. I got a 710 for the quantitative which is in the 73 percentile. For my analytical writing score I got a 4.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty happy with the score that I got for the verbal part of the test. The “Interpreting Your GRE Scores” document that they sent along with the scores stated that the mean for this score in Engineering is 468. Even in the Humanities the mean is 545, so I guess I did pretty good for an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quantitative score I got, 710, is right about par with the Engineering mean of 719. I actually thought I had bombed this section since I basically ran out of time and guessed a whole bunch. I got really good scores in the practice tests, but I guess I was just really nervous for the test. Hopefully the 710 is good enough for the schools I’m applying to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analytical writing score of 4.5 is also fairly average. The mean for engineers is 4.2. They only give the scores in .5 increments, though. I thought I had done a better job of writing, myself. I tried putting good arguments and whatnot into my essays. Oh well, I guess 4.5 is really nothing to be upset about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I thought the GRE was one of the most stressful things I’ve had to endure. The score you earn in the GRE is definitely a quantitative indicator that schools look at. Having said that, I’m still really skeptical as to how useful it really is. It feels to me like something you need to take for the sake of taking it (and paying $130). I really do hope that I’ll never have to take another GRE in my life again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRE Practice Test Roundup</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/01/05/gre-practice-test-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/01/05/gre-practice-test-roundup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took the GRE a little more than a week ago. While I want to hold off on writing about it until I see my final scores, I will say that it’s really important to prepare for the GRE before taking it. The best way to do this is to take practice tests. The best ones are those that tell you not only which questions you got incorrect, but why you missed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through a lot of these practice tests before taking the real GRE. I really think they do make a difference, especially when it comes to feeling comfortable while taking the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I’d make a list of practice tests that you can use to study for the GRE, since I found them useful myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.princetonreview.com/grad/testprep/testprep.asp?TPRPAGE=80&amp;amp;TYPE=GRE-PRACTICE-TEST&#34;&gt;The Princeton Review&lt;/a&gt; – This is a simple web based practice GRE, and the first one I took. It’s free to take as long as you do a quick registration with the Princeton Review. This practice test tells you how long you took on each question and gives you feedback on each answer (and why each wrong answer is incorrect).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ntis01.ets.org/onyx/powerprepTestTakers.htm&#34;&gt;GRE Powerprep Software&lt;/a&gt; – This software is similar to the Princeton Review, and both are very similar to the actual GRE. This software is free with registration, and includes two tests and some focused practice sections. I found the focused sections to be very useful in preparing for the test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ets.org/Media/Tests/GRE/pdf/gre%20practice%20general%20test.pdf&#34;&gt;GRE Practice General Test&lt;/a&gt; -This isn’t a computer practice test, but a paper one. It’s a sample of the test you would take if you were to do the non computer one. What’s useful with this is it includes a few samples of the writing test, along with some critiques and suggestions on how to make the analytical section better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0009NR67I?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=b00003ph0-20&amp;amp;Code=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0009NR67I&#34;&gt;Kaplan GMAT/GRE/LSAT 2006 Platinum&lt;/a&gt; – While this software isn’t free, it really does help a lot. The Kaplan software includes practice tests and tutorials on how to answer questions, even if you don’t know the answer. While this is useful, it really makes the GRE feel like more of a test on how well you can take tests, and not on general knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any resources that I’ve missed? If so, please let me know in the comments and I’ll update the post if I find that they’re useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder: Apply for FAFSA Now!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/01/01/reminder-apply-for-fafsa-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/01/01/reminder-apply-for-fafsa-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is January 1st, which means that you can now sign up for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://studentaid.gov/h/apply-for-aid/fafsa&#34;&gt;FAFSA&lt;/a&gt; (Free Application for Federal Student Aid). The FAFSA determines your eligibility for stuff like grants, loans and work study, so be sure to apply for it early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my first year of undergrad college, I signed up for the FAFSA, but did so very late. I ended up not getting any work study money. I believe I waited until the very last day. This time, I’m determined to sign up very early… as soon as I find my pesky PIN number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last GRE Practice Test</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/26/last-gre-practice-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/26/last-gre-practice-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished the last (probably) GRE practice test before I take the real one on Wednesday. This was the second test of the Powerprep software test. I got a 540 on the verbal part and a 760 on the quantitative section. I’m pretty happy with the score of 760, which is up quite a bit from my first practice test of 630. I actually think it was lower the first time I took it…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not too worried about the verbal, since I have a feeling I’ll do really well on the written part of the exam. My statement of purpose and personal statement should also prove that I have the verbal skills necessary for grad school work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully my scores will reach all of the universities in time. I’d hate to be taking the GRE for nothing…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRE Delays and Drama</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/20/gre-delays-and-drama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/20/gre-delays-and-drama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to take the general GRE test this morning. Since I would get most of the scores right after the test, and the site said that it would take 10-15 days to send the scores, I thought I would make it in time for all of my applications. It snowed really really hard (at least, for New Mexico) yesterday, so they canceled my test! I had to reschedule for December 27th… I’m not sure if the scores will even make it on time for a few of my schools, now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll go ahead and still apply to all of my schools anyway. I’ll be able to write the GRE scores on the applications. It’s just that the schools might not get the official scores until after the official deadline. I’m not sure how stingy some of these schools are, but I’d like to think they they wouldn’t throw an application outright only because the official GRE scores didn’t make it on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that I’ll have more time to study. I took the “Powerprep” practice GRE test, and I got a fairly high verbal (which I don’t remember, because I retook the verbal part again) and a 700 on the quantitative, which is decent. I was worried because the quantitative questions looked a lot different compared to the previous practice tests that I had taken. Apparently it didn’t make too much of a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad news is that my scores might reach their destination late. And the test was rescheduled for 8am, when my original was at 12 noon. I’m not a morning person, so hopefully I’ll get enough rest for the GRE when I take it in a week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even More Grad Schools That I Might Possibly Apply To</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/even-more-grad-schools-that-i-might-possibly-apply-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/even-more-grad-schools-that-i-might-possibly-apply-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reader demaws commented on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/my-application-list-for-computer-science-and-related-schools/&#34;&gt;Application List&lt;/a&gt; with a few other schools. I figured I should take a quick look at them to see if they’re application worthy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;carnegie-mellon&#34;&gt;Carnegie Mellon &lt;a href=&#34;#carnegie-mellon&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hcii.cmu.edu/&#34;&gt;Master’s in HCI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 31st, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Carnegie Mellon is one of the more highly ranked and prestigious schools out there. Their HCI program is different from many others because it only takes a year to finish. The program runs from Fall of a given year to the Summer of the next. The website states that the program does not financially support its students, but occasionally a teaching assistantship will come up for students with a CS background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like there would really be no time to do research while taking so many courses in one semester, on top of doing a teaching assistantship! There is a part time option, so I could probably apply with that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iowa-state-university&#34;&gt;Iowa State University &lt;a href=&#34;#iowa-state-university&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hci.iastate.edu/description.php&#34;&gt;Master’s in Human Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 1st, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Apparently, the HCI program at Iowa State is very highly ranked. I took a look at their website. It looks like they have some interesting courses. For example, “Interaction Methods for Emerging Technologies” and “Organizational and Social Implications of Human Computer Interaction.” Also noteworthy is that that “All students accepted into the HCI program will receive a half-time graduate assistantship.” I’m not really sure what that means. I guess that all students can go part time fully paid. I’ll have to email and ask though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it seems that they have a pre-application before the actual application. Luckily, the pre application is free, so I’ll probably be taking advantage of that fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-of-maryland&#34;&gt;University of Maryland &lt;a href=&#34;#university-of-maryland&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: Master’s in Computer Science, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.umd.edu/hcil/&#34;&gt;HCI Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Deadline: December 15th, 2006&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Maryland has a Human Computer Interaction research group, but no actual department. Therefore, I’d have to apply to CS and then do research within the HCI group. Their group certainly looks like a lively bunch of people. Unfortunately, the deadline is in… 5 days. So I don’t think I’ll be applying due to time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stanford&#34;&gt;Stanford &lt;a href=&#34;#stanford&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: MS in Computer Science, &lt;a href=&#34;http://hci.stanford.edu/&#34;&gt;HCI Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Deadline: December 12th, 2006&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Stanford has a pretty rockin’ HCI group too, it seems. Unfortunately, it’s Stanford, and I’m not a perfect robot. Also, the deadline is in two days, which is kind of cutting it close… I’d apply if I thought I had a chance, and if I could turn back time (which would probably look good in my resume).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got a Reply From Berkeley’s iSchool</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/got-a-reply-from-berkeleys-ischool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/10/got-a-reply-from-berkeleys-ischool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow up from the last post, I got a reply regarding a few questions I had about Berkeley’s iSchool. Mainly, I just reiterated my concerns about the perceived legitimacy of “Information Schools” opposed to pure Computer Science. I also asked about the availability of funding for Master’s students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reply was that the reputation of the program over at Berkeley is rising. Of course, I’ll take that info with a grain of salt, but the person who replied to me said that many companies like to recruit at the iSchool, and had some other facts to back up the claim. My question about funding was answered more indirectly. I was just told that there exist many research opportunities with companies. They also mentioned that Yahoo has a research lab at Berkeley, which is kinda cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m glad that someone at Berkeley spent the time to answer my questions. Now I’m just waiting on UC Irvine and Georgia Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacting Grad Schools, And Waiting For Replies…</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/07/contacting-grad-schools-and-waiting-for-replies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/12/07/contacting-grad-schools-and-waiting-for-replies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last post, I mentioned that the University of Michigan had a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://mblog.lib.umich.edu/sitrenches1/&#34;&gt;admissions blog&lt;/a&gt; that included a contact email in case any prospective students had questions. I actually had a few questions, so I decided to send an email. I also figured that I should send emails to all of the institutions that I was thinking of applying to. I sent similar emails (though they each had specific questions about each program) to Georgia Tech, Virginia Tech, UC Irvine, and Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a very long and thoughtful response from Laura Elgas at Michigan. Her email really went above and beyond what I was expecting to receive. She answered all of my questions and even offered to set up a telephone appointment so I could speak with her directly! Suffice it to say, I have a very positive impression of the program at Michigan now. It really means a lot to me that a real human would reply and help me out with this difficult process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got a personal reply from Virginia Tech. They simply stated that I seemed to be a good match with their program based on the info I told them (I also sent them the URL for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notecentric.com/&#34;&gt;Notecentric&lt;/a&gt;). Most of my questions were answered, though they skipped a few. They politely asked that I keep in touch once I’ve actually submitted my application. This is about on par with what I would expect to receive. I understand that most schools don’t have much time to respond personally to emails, so the reply I got very much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both UC Irvine and Berkeley sent me automatic replies. The UC Irvine one had a lot of general grad school information. It said that I should send the message again if my questions weren’t answered. I did. The Berkeley email just stated that I should be receiving a reply shortly. This was five days ago. Hopefully I’ll get something from both of them soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Georgia Tech sent me nothing. Incidentally, I had sent a message to them a month or so ago that didn’t get a reply either. I don’t know who’s running the recruiting over at Georgia Tech, but they haven’t impressed me. I really don’t expect to get a reply from them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in summary, Michigan is really awesome at recruiting, VT is good. UC Irvine and Berkeley still haven’t sent me anything, but it’s only been 5 days. Still a long turnaround time, I think. Georgia Tech doesn’t seem to care about its prospective students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some schools have made me feel very excited to apply, others have given me the cold shoulder. While the academic strength of a program is really important, I think that the people skills of a department really reflect a lot as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Additional Schools That I Might Apply To</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/26/some-additional-schools-that-i-might-apply-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/26/some-additional-schools-that-i-might-apply-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found a few more schools that have good looking programs that I’d be interested in applying to. With these two, my school count would go up to 7. I’m not too sure that’s playing it too safe, or not safe enough. Here are the additional schools and my reasoning for wanting to apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cornell&#34;&gt;Cornell &lt;a href=&#34;#cornell&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infosci.cornell.edu/grad/&#34;&gt;PhD in Information Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 1, 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Cornell has a program similar to a few of the schools that I’m already planning on applying to. Right now, they only have a PhD program in Information Science, so I’d have to go that route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not really too opposed to applying as a PhD student; I’m just not completely sure about studying for another 4-5 years as opposed to 2 years. The program at Cornell seems fairly multidisciplinary, with courses in communication, cognition, and social aspects of information. It seems like a nice program, if I can get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-of-michigan&#34;&gt;University of Michigan &lt;a href=&#34;#university-of-michigan&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.umich.edu/msi/default.htm&#34;&gt;Master of Science in Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: February 5th, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: The University of Michigan offers a Masters degree in Information. The program offers courses like “Design of Complex Web Sites” and “Computer-Supported Cooperative Work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing I found was that the website had &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.umich.edu/applying/subscribe.htm&#34;&gt;links to school blogs&lt;/a&gt;. There were a few from students, as well as an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mblog.lib.umich.edu/sitrenches1/&#34;&gt;Admissions Blog&lt;/a&gt;. The admissions blog seems to have been set up specifically to help prospective students through the process. Very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More GRE Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/19/more-gre-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/19/more-gre-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I took that same practice GRE test a few times yesterday. Unfortunately, it looks like I’m getting duplicate questions, so the accuracy of the scores is probably not as good. I got 690 on both verbal and quantitative this time. I wonder why I keep getting the same on both parts…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time through the math part, I actually ran out of time. This is because I took a more leisurely pace and suddenly the questions got more demanding. I suppose it’s because the test adapts itself to you. So if you answer a lot of questions wrong in the beginning, it’ll throw some easier ones at you. If you answer them correctly, the questions get harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually got a lot of new questions in the verbal part. It seems like I answered those correctly too, so hopefully it’ll be the same way in the real test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll try looking for another practice test with different questions so I can make sure that I don’t come into the test overconfident. I’d really like to not run out of time on the test. Also, I’ve haven’t really practiced the written part of the test, but I have been writing a lot in this (and other) blogs, which will probably help quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Application Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/15/random-application-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 22:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/15/random-application-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I talked to another past professor of mine today because I had heard he knows a lot about applying to grad school. He wouldn’t admit mastery of the subject, but he did say that he probably knows a hell of a lot more than I do about it right now. That fact is incontestable. Anyway, he gave me some tips that I hadn’t heard yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, he went through the process of how he looks at grad school applications at our own school. Apparently, some aid goes through and writes a summary of the entire application which goes in the front. Next he flips through the transcripts without much emphasis. He reminds me that there are hundreds of these things to read through. At a place like Stanford we’d be talking somewhere around 5,000…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next he looks at the statement of purpose. This is one of the more important parts, since it shows that the applicant has a clear goal, and that the applicant can write well. He tells me there should be a beginning, middle, and end, much like a story. He also told me that the statement of purpose should make people at the program say “hey, this guy is cool, we should get him in here!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, he goes through the letters of recommendation. These are the closest thing to a third party that he has to make a decision on the applicant. They should really say things like “I worked with so and so on this and that, and he really impressed me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t take the time to build the kinds of relationships to warrant those kinds of letters. The software engineering professor that I’m working with right now will be able to write something closer to that, but not this professor. All he can really say is that I was a fairly good student and that I was more willing to go up to the chalkboard than others in the same class. Though it’s not a tier 1 type of letter, I’ll still ask him since I do recall doing well in the class, and the professor is honest when he tells me he can’t write a stellar letter. At the very least, it won’t hurt (like a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invisible_Man&#34;&gt;Dr. Bledsoe letter&lt;/a&gt; would).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we talked about the schools that I’m applying to. Apparently my undergraduate adviser went to Georgia Tech, so I should talk to him about faculty there. Apparently it helps to have a faculty at the school who would be familiar with me, so when my application pops up, they might push it harder. I’ll definitely try contacting some faculty, once I’ve turned in my applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing A Statement of Purpose</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/writing-a-statement-of-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 22:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/writing-a-statement-of-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So one of the (supposedly) most important parts of the grad school application packet is the statement of purpose. The SOP is basically an essay explaining how awesome you are and why the university should accept you as a grad student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Georgia Tech and Virginia Tech do not list the statement of purpose as a required part of the application. UC Irvine says that it’s part of a complete application, but doesn’t describe it at all. Lehigh has this to say about the statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(It is) a brief statement of career and research objectives. Essays should articulate clearly your experience and goals. Half a page to two pages is sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UC Berkeley’s iSchool has quite a bit more to say about the statement of purpose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Statement of Purpose provides the application reviewers with information about your professional goals, your intended areas of study within a given academic program, and your reasons for applying to this specific program of study. It becomes a crucial element in the admissions decision process since it conveys to the faculty reviewers how well-prepared you are to undertake graduate study in information management and systems; what you intend to do with the degree; and what specializations you wish to pursue within the Master’s program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your written statement should succinctly explain your reasons for applying to the iSchool, briefly review your relevant academic preparation and work experience, and describe your future professional goals once the degree is acquired. The focus should be on your preparation, experience, and aims rather than a discussion of the trends or the importance of information management and systems in general. The most successful statements are 1-2 pages in length and focus on the strengths and experiences of the applicant, providing the reviewers with evidence and justification for admitting those applicants who are qualified and well-suited for the iSchool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ph.D. applicants will need to also make clear their research interests and agenda, as well as which iSchool faculty they are interested in researching with specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I’ve written a very rough draft of the statement of purpose. I intend to clean it up quite a bit, as well as drafting a different one for each school I apply to. Given the lack of requirement/description from three of the five schools, I question how important the statement of purpose really is. I’ll still work hard in it though, since it’s one of the few parts of the application that is completely within my control (unlike transcripts, which I can’t really change anymore…).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Application List For Computer Science and Related Schools</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/my-application-list-for-computer-science-and-related-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2006 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/14/my-application-list-for-computer-science-and-related-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After taking quite a bit of time considering schools and departments, I’ve come up with a list of schools I’ll be applying to. I suppose they’re still subject to change, but here’s what I’ve got (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;georgia-tech&#34;&gt;Georgia Tech &lt;a href=&#34;#georgia-tech&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/content/view/731/464/&#34;&gt;MS in Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: February 1, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Georgia Tech seems to be one of the more, if not the most progressive schools in the nation when it comes to computer science. Their MS program in HCI has a bunch of interesting courses like Design of Online Communities and Collaborative Computing. In addition to the MS in HCI, the MS in CS also allows students to specialize in a field. The fields include intelligent systems, networking and communications, and HCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virginia-tech&#34;&gt;Virginia Tech &lt;a href=&#34;#virginia-tech&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hosting.cs.vt.edu/gpc/MSreqts.html&#34;&gt;MS in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 15, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Virginia Tech is one of the few schools that i found that has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hci.vt.edu/&#34;&gt;HCI group&lt;/a&gt;. Virginia Tech is fairly well ranked in terms of Engineering schools. Another plus is that they seem to offer good funding to their MS thesis students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uc-irvine&#34;&gt;UC Irvine &lt;a href=&#34;#uc-irvine&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/grad/degrees/index.php?track=inf-ict&#34;&gt;MS in Interactive and Collaborative Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 15, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: UC Irvine is one of the schools I wrote about earlier with a specialized degree program. In this case, the field is referred to as “Informatics.” They have their own &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/%7Ecorps/&#34;&gt;ICT group&lt;/a&gt; which is a huge plus in terms of research capability. “Interactive and Collaborative Technology” is exactly what I’d like to do research in, and I’m hopeful that I’ll be accepted into the program. Apparently, their MS students have a chance to get financial assistance through teaching assistantships and whatnot, so I’ll apply for the MS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lehigh-university&#34;&gt;Lehigh University &lt;a href=&#34;#lehigh-university&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www3.lehigh.edu/engineering/cse/academics/grad/masterscicompsci.asp&#34;&gt;MS in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 15, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: I had never heard of Lehigh University until I saw the name on multiple top engineering school lists. After doing some research, it seems like Lehigh is a good fit for me, since it includes a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wume.cse.lehigh.edu/&#34;&gt;Web Understanding, Modeling, and Evaluation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. It appears that Lehigh is preparing to branch its Computer Engineering program into an Intelligent Information Systems Engineering and Software Systems Engineering as well, so it might be a good time for me to apply to their program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uc-berkeley&#34;&gt;UC Berkeley &lt;a href=&#34;#uc-berkeley&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Degree: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ischool.berkeley.edu/programs/masters&#34;&gt;MS in Information Sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline: January 5, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: The iSchool at Berkeley is relatively new: the school was created in 1994. The school is also very small. Only 40 of 200 master’s students are accepted each year. I have a feeling that the projects that I’ve done might make me interesting to the school, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll try using the iSchool as my “long shot” school and just apply to see if I can make it. The courses all seem very cool, with names like “XML Foundations” and “The Quality of Information.” I would really love to get into this school, as it seems like they’re on the forefront of this field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing For The GRE With Practice Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/08/preparing-for-the-gre-with-practice-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/08/preparing-for-the-gre-with-practice-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that will hopefully help in my grad school admissions are my standardized test scores. I remember getting a decent SAT score, and I never even took the ACT. Luckily, I still got into my school of choice, UNM. Well, it was my only choice, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard people say that the GRE really did a number on them. They went in unprepared and suffered the consequences. While a high GRE score probably won’t guarantee that I’ll get accepted into the more difficult universities, it definitely won’t hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and tried the practice test over at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://princetonreview.com/&#34;&gt;Princeton Review&lt;/a&gt;. The first time I tried it, I was fairly distracted and I was going fast to see how long it would take. I ended up taking about 2/3 of the time for both parts. I skipped the writing parts, since they wouldn’t get graded anyway unless I paid for it. I got a pretty bad score the first time. I don’t remember what I got though, since I deleted it and tried again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the test questions are somewhat randomized. I only got two or so duplicates. The second time through, I took more time and tried being more careful. I still missed a few questions. The cool thing about the practice tests is that you can see exactly what you missed and get an explanation of why you missed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final scores on the second test run were 630 for both the verbal and quantitative sections. While that’s great for the verbal score, as an Engineering major, my quantitative score needs to be much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the questions I missed, they were a mix of careless mistakes and lack of trigonometry/probability knowledge. I guess it’s not really a lack so much as a need to brush up. I haven’t done any math involving trig or probability in a really long time. Since I know what I need to work on, I should be able to raise my scores before I take the real test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t taken the GRE and haven’t done any preparation, I’d suggest at least trying out the practice test over at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://princetonreview.com/&#34;&gt;Princeton Review&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t know how close it is to the real GRE, but at least I’m feeling more confident about my strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Degree in Computer Science vs. Information Technology vs. Informatics?</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/06/graduate-degree-in-computer-science-vs.-information-technology-vs.-informatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/06/graduate-degree-in-computer-science-vs.-information-technology-vs.-informatics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So getting a bachelor’s degree in Computer Science was a pretty easy decision for me to make. There’s not a “Computer Engineering” degree at my school, and “Electrical Engineering” is too circuity for my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to do research in stuff like social computing and computational linguistics. While looking for departments with research in these fields, it’s become evident this kind of research doesn’t typically fall in the Computer Science field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computational linguistics stuff falls under the linguistics departments for a lot of schools. While I like the idea of researching more linguistics, I don’t know if I want to get a graduate level degree in it. It would make more sense to me to get a MD or PhD in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social computing field is actually fairly new. It seems like more and more schools are starting “Information Technology” departments that are separate from their Computer Science ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such school is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rit.edu/&#34;&gt;Rochester Institute of Technology&lt;/a&gt;. RIT even has a section of its website dedicated to explaining the differences between &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.it.rit.edu/it/undergrad/whichpathBS.maml&#34;&gt;Information Technology, Computer Science, Software Engineering, Computer Engineering and Information Systems&lt;/a&gt; by likening it to the development of a video game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computer engineer would design the actual game platform, the hardware and low-level software. The software engineer would design the software architecture in which specific games would be developed and facilitate on-time development of reliable components. The computer scientist would develop efficient underlying algorithms for the game engines. The IT professional would focus on specific games from the player’s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, I’d see myself as either a software engineer, computer scientist, or IT person. When it’s described like this, none of the degrees seem “bad.” I think, however, that there’s a sort of stigma when talking about “IT” people. Mainly the idea that they’re the “tech support guy” who fixes dumb peoples’ computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found yet another “new” degree at UC Irvine called the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/grad/degrees/index.php?track=inf-ict&#34;&gt;“Concentration in Informatics Track in Interactive and Collaborative Technology.”&lt;/a&gt; This one really seems to fit the bill in terms of the type of research and learning that I want to do. UC Irvine even has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ics.uci.edu/%7Ecorps/&#34;&gt;ICT&lt;/a&gt; (Interactive and Collaborative Technologies) group with a bunch of people I’d probably like working with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, I think the only reservation I’d have is getting into a relatively “new” degree program, and the perceived “illegitimacy” when compared to a PhD in the almighty “Computer Science!” Then again, it might be time for the monolithic Computer Science degree to be broken into smaller, more specialized fields of study…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last “alternative” graduate program that I’ll mention is at Georgia Tech. They offer an MS in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/content/view/731/464/&#34;&gt;“Human-Computer Interaction”&lt;/a&gt; and a PhD in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/content/view/190/136/&#34;&gt;“Human-Centered Computing.”&lt;/a&gt; Georgia Tech really seems to be one of the more progressive schools when it comes to computing degrees, and I’d be really happy to go there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I read about these alternative graduate programs, the more I think that a standard graduate degree in Computer Science is becoming less relevant in a quickly changing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do you think? Is the traditional Computer Science track the way to go? Are these new fangled degrees nothing but semantic sugar? Please let me know in the comments, as I’m not quite decided on this myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Go To Grad School?</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/why-go-to-grad-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 16:10:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/why-go-to-grad-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess a good introductory post would be discussing why I’m considering grad school. I suppose that most people go to grad school because they want to make more money, or they want to be elite. Some people want to be professors, so graduate school is an obvious choice for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to, I could probably just walk away from school after getting my BS in Computer Science and make a comfortable living on that. I do hear a lot of people who did just that, and the consensus is that they wish that they had gone on to grad school. They have tons of payments to make (house, car, etc.) and it’s really impossible for them to pursue further education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I’d rather explore all of my possibilities. I’ve actually enjoyed the higher level electives in CS that I took, so more of that would be excellent. Of course, then there’s research and teaching. There are a few things I’d like to research, and teaching is pretty fun too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to say is that I want to see if grad school will work out for me. Maybe it will, and maybe it won’t. Not that I’m going into this half-assed or anything. If I don’t end up going to grad school, I’ll most likely be able to find a well paying job. If I do make it in, it’ll be a whole new experience for me. I think it’s a win-win situation either way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to The Grad School Chronicles!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/welcome-to-the-grad-school-chronicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 15:12:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/welcome-to-the-grad-school-chronicles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is yet another blog for me, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hung-truong.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Hung Truong&lt;/a&gt;, to keep up to date. I’ve been searching for CS Graduate Schools and thought it would be a good idea to impart the information I’ve gained onto the web. Most graduate school info online tends to be dry and written from the perspective of someone who’s been through it all already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog will be written by someone who’s still figuring out the process, so hopefully it’ll also be helpful to others who are going through the same thing. I’m still in the very early stages of the grad school process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, this blog will chronicle the steps I take from figuring out how to apply, collecting the letters of acceptance, choosing which school to go to, and then my experiences during grad school itself. Hopefully I’ll get past the second step, at least!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned quite a big just from talking to professors and advisers. Stuff that isn’t really available online, either. In addition to writing about what I’m doing to further the process, I’ll also try to post tips and information that I think is not so common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting, and I hope you get some use out of The Grad School Chronicles*!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*At least until I come up with a better name!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
