<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Site on The Grad School Chronicles</title>
    <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/site/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Site on The Grad School Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hung Truong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 16:10:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Go To Grad School?</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/why-go-to-grad-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 16:10:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2006/11/04/why-go-to-grad-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess a good introductory post would be discussing why I’m considering grad school. I suppose that most people go to grad school because they want to make more money, or they want to be elite. Some people want to be professors, so graduate school is an obvious choice for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to, I could probably just walk away from school after getting my BS in Computer Science and make a comfortable living on that. I do hear a lot of people who did just that, and the consensus is that they wish that they had gone on to grad school. They have tons of payments to make (house, car, etc.) and it’s really impossible for them to pursue further education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I’d rather explore all of my possibilities. I’ve actually enjoyed the higher level electives in CS that I took, so more of that would be excellent. Of course, then there’s research and teaching. There are a few things I’d like to research, and teaching is pretty fun too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to say is that I want to see if grad school will work out for me. Maybe it will, and maybe it won’t. Not that I’m going into this half-assed or anything. If I don’t end up going to grad school, I’ll most likely be able to find a well paying job. If I do make it in, it’ll be a whole new experience for me. I think it’s a win-win situation either way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
