<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Admission Offers on The Grad School Chronicles</title>
    <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/admission-offers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Admission Offers on The Grad School Chronicles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Hung Truong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 13:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/tags/admission-offers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iowa State: Super Late Rejection!!!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/06/01/iowa-state-super-late-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/06/01/iowa-state-super-late-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got a rejection email from Iowa State. They certainly took their time to inform me of my rejection!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of Jim Oliver, HCI graduate program chair, thank you very much for your application to our graduate program. We are very pleased to be able to consider students such as you. However, we only accept students for whom we can provide research assistantships. Unfortunately, we receive applications from many more highly qualified students than we are able to support. We, therefore, cannot offer you admission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trust that you will be admitted elsewhere and wish you the best of luck in your graduate studies. Thank you again for considering Iowa State University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already accepted over at Michigan, so this is kind of pointless to post. Except that it’s way funny seeing this email in June. Ah well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Irvine Bren School of ICS: Rejection!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/uc-irvine-bren-school-of-ics-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/uc-irvine-bren-school-of-ics-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I applied to the UC Irvine Bren School of ICS under the informatics track. Sadly, today I was denied admission via email. So now I’m 2 for 6 in applying to grad schools with 3 of the 4 rejections being concrete, and one in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UC Irvine did seem like a pretty cool place to apply for grad school, so I’m a little bummed that I didn’t meet their requirements. Looking at it geographically, it looks like I did better the farther NorthEast I went. Maybe I should’ve applied at MIT!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virginia Tech Computer Science Program: Acceptance!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/virginia-tech-computer-science-program-acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2007 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/04/05/virginia-tech-computer-science-program-acceptance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a letter in the mail today from Virginia Tech. Surprisingly, it was an acceptance letter! I got into their CS program! Pretty cool. The letter came fairly late, though, and without any mention of scholarships, so I’m assuming I’m one of their second or third tier choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve already accepted to go to Michigan (with a nice funding package), but it’s nice to see that I made it into another program at least. I think the program at Virginia Tech is actually pretty competitive, so it makes me feel better about being rejected from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/05/university-of-california-berkeley-ischool-rejection/&#34;&gt;Berkeley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/georgia-tech-hci-program-rejection/&#34;&gt;Georgia Tech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My record is now 2 of 6, with 2 being rejections and 2 not yet known. Like I said though, it doesn’t really matter since I got into my top school, but pride-wise, this makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgia Tech, HCI Program: Rejection!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/georgia-tech-hci-program-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/28/georgia-tech-hci-program-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so this news is sorta late, but I figured I’d post this anyway. Remember how I wrote about how Georgia Tech wasn’t responding to my emails? I finally got a response! A rejection! Yeah, that’s right, Georgia Tech only takes the time to respond to a candidate when they’re rejecting them. How nice. Here’s the letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Hung:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry to inform you that your application to Georgia Tech’s MS program in Human-Computer Interaction has been declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many applicants we are not able to admit. The applicant pool was significantly larger than in recent years, and the overall quality of applicants even higher than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like advice on strengthening your application and trying again next year, I’ll be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have our best wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least they offered to give me advice on helping my application. I actually emailed them back immediately and got an “out of town” autoreply. So they wrote me this denial from out of town?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not too upset about this. Georgia Tech showed that they didn’t care about their MS students even before sending me this rejection. I spoke with some other students at the University of Michigan visiting days and there was pretty much a consensus that Georgia Tech treats their MS students with dollar signs in their eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of California, Berkeley iSchool: Rejection!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/05/university-of-california-berkeley-ischool-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/05/university-of-california-berkeley-ischool-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just got an email from the iSchool at Berkeley. It reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The admissions committee of the School of Information has reviewed all of the materials submitted with your application. I regret to inform you that you have not been accepted for admission to the Fall 2007 entering class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well! I’m pretty happy that I got accepted to Michigan already. Berkeley looked like a pretty good school, but it was my “probably too hard to get in” one, so I don’t feel too bad. I wonder if all of the schools will be sending these admission messages through email… Seems to be a new trend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michigan School of Information Scholarship Update!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/01/michigan-school-of-information-scholarship-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/03/01/michigan-school-of-information-scholarship-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got an email today from Michigan offering me a half tuition merit scholarship! This brings the cost of tuition down to the same amount that an in-state resident would pay. Scholarship students also get travel expenses refunded in order to visit the school on the SI: Visiting Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The visiting days include an optional tour of the campus, housing, or libraries, and then a few activities with some of the student groups. It seems like fun, and I’d really like to be able to visit a school before committing to going there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully everything will work out and I’ll be able to visit on the scheduled day. I’m actually going to be out of town on the day before, so I’d have to fly directly to Michigan. I can probably make it work, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Michigan School of Information Acceptance Email Received!</title>
      <link>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/02/22/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-acceptance-email-received/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hung-truong.com/gradschool/2007/02/22/university-of-michigan-school-of-information-acceptance-email-received/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received a letter of acceptance from the University of Michigan School of Information. It was one of my top choices, so I’m happy to be accepted for admission. Actually, right now it’s a “conditional” admission, since they said they’re having issues with my official transcript, but I’m sure that won’t be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still haven’t heard anything about possible financial aid or scholarships yet. Hopefully I’ll be offered something. I think it would be very hard for me to go to school for more than $14,000 a semester without any assistance. Maybe I’ll receive that information at a later date. Edit: I got an email saying that the financial aid offers will be given in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m very happy about getting the email. I hope the other schools will send their Acceptance/Rejection (I hope not!) letters soon. One thing I found interesting was that Michigan sent me the acceptance letter by email. I think almost all schools will only send this information out by snail mail. Not that it’s bad or anything, I’d rather find out as soon as possible! It’s pretty cool that Michigan is hip enough with technology to use email though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
